# **Agus Pranyoto**

JUNIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER
PT. SUMMIT GLOBAL TEKNOLOGI



agusprnyt@gmail.com | +6285771559371 | East Jakarta, Jakarta | agus-pranyoto.web.app

#### **Profile**

A passionate frontend engineer dedicated to crafting user-friendly and responsive websites and web applications. Proficient in React js, Vue js, Next js, and Nuxt js. Equipped with 4 months of professional work experience and 9 months of internship experience in web development, as well as holding 2 professional certificates in frontend development.

#### **Education**

Mercu Buana University

2023

- · Bachelor of Informatics Engineering
- GPA: 3.76

SMKN 26 Jakarta

2018

· Mechanical Engineering

## **Professional Certifications**

Front End Engineering Bootcamp By Kampus Merdeka X Ruangguru

Jun 2023

- · Build Student Portal Website with React Js and Chakra UI
- Junior Web Programmer By Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi

Apr 2023

Build an Online Shop website with Codeigniter 3 and Bootstrap

## **Experience**

Junior Frontend Engineer | PT. Summit Global Teknologi - Full Time

Jan 2024 - Present

- Create responsive unique selling proposition websites with Vue.js, Nuxt.js, and SCSS
- · Slice designs from Photoshop to HTML and SCSS
- Create animation effects with SwiperJs and ScrollMagic
- · Collaborate effectively with teams, utilizing Git for version control and code management

#### Front End Engineering | PT. Surya Citra Media - Intern

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Install VPN Global Protect to be able to access the company's repository
- Clone the SCM Hub project to the local repository
- · Redesigned the SCM hub project using Vuexy
- Created the Frontend view of the SCM Hub project using Vue is 3 and Laravel 9

#### Web Developer | PT Sugity Creatives - Intern

Apr 2022 - Jun 2022

- Design a Truck Arrival Monitoring Website Using Codeigniter 3
- · Install XAMPP tools on the delivery department's computer
- Test the Truck Arrival Monitoring Website Using Codeigniter 3
- · Create and print a QR Code to be scanned by drivers from supplier companies

#### Quality Assurance | PT. Yamaha Music Manufacturing Indonesia - Full Time Jun 2018 - May 2019

- · Inspect musical instruments produced by the production department
- · Collaborate with the production department
- · Worked together with team to achieve daily targets
- Ensure work results are in accordance with standard operational procedures
- · Daily meeting to discuss targets to be achieved

#### Production Operator | PT. Braja Mukti Cakra - Full Time

Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

- Operate CNC machines (Computer Numerical Control)
- Worked together with team to achieve daily targets
- · Ensure work results are in accordance with standard operational procedures
- · Daily meeting to discuss targets to be achieved

### **Skills**

React.js

Vue.js

Next.js

Nuxt.js

JavaScript

Typescript

Redux

• HTML5

· CSS3

Firebase

· Git Version Control

MySQL

RESTful API

· UI/UX Design

CodeIgniter 3

Laravel 9

# Language

- · Bahasa Indonesia (Native)
- English (Intermediate)